Finding Aid for James J. Blanchard Papers, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library
- Washington Office, 1983-1990
  - Peter Kyriacopolous (Analyst), 1983-1990
    - Legislative Action File, 1983-1990
      - Transportation, 1984-1990
        - State Police, 1984-1985 (Box 244)
        - User Fees (Lake Carriers), 1985 (Box 244)
        - Zilwaukee Bridge, 1987-1988 (Box 244)
      - Verona Well Field, 1984 (Box 244)
      - Wetlands, 1987 (Box 244)
- Governor's Residence Files
  The Governor's Residence Files series consist of materials maintained at Governor Blanchard's Lansing residence. These files came to the library separate from the major corpus of governor's papers. Except for the subseries - Lansing residence events file - these materials overlap in subject content materials found in the other series of the collection.
  - Topical files, 1982-1990
    - Achievements, 1989-1990 (Box 246)
    - Advance Corps, 1986 (Box 246)
    - A.I.D.S., 1988 (Box 246)
    - Annual Report of Washington Office, 1985 (Box 246)
    - Anti-Trust Enforcement, 1987 (Box 246)
    - Apartheid, 1985-1986 (Box 246)
    - Attorney General, 1985-1990 (Box 246)
    - Australia, trade mission, 1986 (Box 246)
    - Auto Emissions Program, 1987 (Box 246)
    - Auto Import Restraints, 1984 (Box 246)
    - Black Ministers, 1987-1989 (Box 246)
    - Blec Manufacturing, 1987 (Box 246)
    - Bonds Ratings, 1986 (Box 246)
    - Bowman, Robert, 1987-1988 (Box 246)
    - Business Partnership, 1989-1990 (Box 246)
    - Capitol Building Authority, 1987-1988 (Box 246)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1985 (Box 246)
    - Charities, Hunger, 1984-1985 (Box 246)
    - Charity, 1984-1990 (Box 246)
    - Christmas Tree, 1987-1990 (Box 246)
    - Clean Air Act, 1989-1990 (Box 246)
    - Cobo Hall, 1984 (Box 246)
    - Cockrel, Kenneth, 1989 (Box 246)
    - Co-Generation Projects, 1987-1988 (Box 246)
    - Commerce, 1985-1990; 7 folders (Box 246)
    - Comparative State Income Tax Burden, 1981-1982 (Box 246)
    - Competitiveness, Michigan Jobs, 1986-1988 (Box 246)
    - Conflict of Interest Policy, 1986 (Box 246)
    - Congress, 1986-1988 (Box 246)
    - Constitutional Amendment Process, 1988 (Box 246)
    - Consumers Power Company, 1984-1988 (Box 246)
    - Consumers Power Plant, Mid, 1985 (Box 246)
    - Conrail Issue, 1985 (Box 246)
    - 1984 Convention, 1983-1984 (Box 246)
    - Counsel of Great Lakes Governors, 1986-1990 (Box 246)
    - Cuomo Commission Report, 1988 (Box 246)
    - Dayton-Hudson Corporation, 1987 (Box 247)
    - 1988 Democratic Convention, 1988 (Box 247)
    - 1988 Democratic Convention, Platform Committee, 1987, 1987-1988 (Box 247)
    - Democratic Governors Association, 1987-1989 (Box 247)
    - Detroit Compact, 1987 (Box 247)
    - Detroit Financial Services Center, 1987 (Box 247)
    - Detroit Symphony Orchestra, 1987 (Box 247)
    - Detroit Tigers, 1989 (Box 247)
    - Detroit Utility Tax, 1990 (Box 247)
    - Divestiture, 1988-1989 (Box 247)
    - Domestic Markets, Task Force, 1989 (Box 247)
    - Economic Alliance for Michigan, 1989 (Box 247)
    - Economic Competitiveness-Osborne Company, 1987 (Box 247)
    - Economic Forums, speech, 1988 (Box 247)
    - Economic Statistics, 1986-1987 (Box 247)
    - EDS, Electronic Data Systems Corporation, 1985 (Box 247)
    - Education, 1984-1990; 2 folders (Box 247)
    - Education Package, 1989 (Box 247)
    - Education Summit, 1989 (Box 247)
    - Election Returns, 1984 (Box 247)
    - Essential Insurance, 1985 (Box 247)
    - European Trip, 1987 (Box 247)
    - Executive Corporations, 1984-1988 (Box 247)
    - Executive Internship Program, 1989 (Box 247)
    - Federal Budget, 1984-1990 (Box 247)
    - Federal Legislation, 1987-1989 (Box 247)
    - Financial Crisis Council, 1982-1983 (Box 247)
    - Ford Motor, 1985-1986 (Box 247)
    - Free Trade Agreement, 1987-1990 (Box 247)
    - Frost, Doug, 1985-1990 (Box 247)
    - Gelman Science, 1988-1989 (Box 247)
    - General Motors, 1986-1989 (Box 247)
    - GM-80, 1984 (Box 247)
    - GMF Robotics, 1985 (Box 247)
    - Governor's Commission on Economic Development, 1983-1989 (Box 247)
    - Grand Prix, 1987-1989 (Box 247)
    - Hazardous Wastes, 1986-1988 (Box 247)
    - Health Care, 1984-1990 (Box 247)
    - Higher Education Commission, 1984 (Box 247)
    - Immigration Reform, 1986-1987 (Box 247)
    - Industrial Competitiveness Conference, 1987 (Box 247)
    - Interdepartmental Meeting, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 247)
    - Investment Group, 1986 (Box 248)
    - Issues, 1989 (Box 248)
    - Japanese Trade, 1985 (Box 248)
    - J.E. Incorporated, 1987 (Box 248)
    - Jefferson-Jackson Speech Information, 1987 (Box 248)
    - Job Training, 1985-1986 (Box 248)
    - Job Training Partnership Act, 1983-1987 (Box 248)
    - Joint Operating Agreement, JOA, 1988-1989 (Box 248)
    - Labor Unions, 1988 (Box 248)
    - LaRouche, Henry "Hank" Wilson, 1986 (Box 248)
    - Large Lakes Conference, 1986 (Box 248)
    - London Trip, 1989 (Box 248)
    - Louisiana-Pacific Corporation, 1983 (Box 248)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste, 1987-1990 (Box 248)
    - MEA Questionnaire, 1990 (Box 248)
    - MBIA, Municipal Bond Investors Assurance Corporation, Seminar / Bermuda, 1988 (Box 248)
    - Mackinac Is, 1985-1989 (Box 248)
    - Malpractice Insurance, 1985-1987 (Box 248)
    - McClouth Steel, 1987-1988 (Box 248)
    - Medicaid-Quality Control Legislation, 1985 (Box 248)
    - Michigan Development Foundation, 1988 (Box 248)
    - Michigan Opportunity Card, 1988 (Box 248)
    - Michigan Partnership for New Education, 1989 (Box 248)
    - Michigan Education Trust, 1986-1990 (Box 248)
    - Michigan Soft Drink Association Law Suit, 1990 (Box 248)
    - Michigan State University, 1988-1990 (Box 248)
    - Michigan Strategic Fund, 1987 (Box 248)
    - Midwest Compact, 1987-1988 (Box 248)
    - Midwest Governors, 1989 (Box 248)
    - Mitsubishi, 1985 (Box 248)
    - Monte Carlo Trip, 1987 (Box 248)
    - Moody Case, 1982-1983 (Box 248)
    - Murphy, Daniel, 1986 (Box 248)
    - National Governors Association, NGA, 1984-1990; 4 folders (Box 248)
    - National Governors Association Annual Meetings, 1988 (Box 248)
    - NCMS, National Center for Manufacturing Sciences, 1987-1988 (Box 248)
    - Office of the Great Lakes, 1988-1990 (Box 248)
    - Oil / Gas Crisis, 1990; 2 folders (Box 248)
    - Oil Tanker Spill, 1990 (Box 248)
    - Pearsall, Paul, 1988 (Box 248)
    - PPG's Michigan Potash Project, 1985 (Box 248)
    - Personal Letters, 1987-1990; 4 folders (Box 249)
    - Peters, Tom, 1986 (Box 249)
    - Peterson, Premier David, 1987-1989 (Box 249)
    - Petition Drives, 1885 (Box 249)
    - Plant Closing Demonstration Project, 1986 (Box 249)
    - Polls, Newsweek 1988 Election, 1988 (Box 249)
    - Presidential Delegate Selection Caucuses, 1984 (Box 249)
    - Product Liability, 1987-1990 (Box 249)
    - Project 500, 1988-1990 (Box 249)
    - Project on Future of Higher Education, 1984 (Box 249)
    - Proposal A, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 249)
    - Proposal C, 1984 (Box 249)
    - Proposals C and D, 1988 (Box 249)
    - Reagan, 1987 (Box 249)
    - Research Excellence Fund, 1985 (Box 249)
    - Richards, Libby, 1987 (Box 249)
    - S & L Crisis, 1989-1990 (Box 249)
    - Saturn, 1985 (Box 249)
    - Secchia, Peter, 1989 (Box 249)
    - Sesquia Books, 1988-1989 (Box 249)
    - Shoreline Review, 1989 (Box 249)
    - Single Business Tax, 1987-1988 (Box 249)
    - Small Business High Technology Institute, 1987
    - Solvency Day, 1986 (Box 249)
    - Speakers', Bureau, 1988-1990 (Box 250)
    - Speeches, 1982-1988 (Box 250)
    - Statistics, 1982-1983 (Box 250)
    - Successors To Governors Office, 1985-1986 (Box 250)
    - Superconducting Supercollider, 1987-1989 (Box 250)
    - Tax Reform Plan, 1986 (Box 250)
    - Third District, 1985 (Box 250)
    - Toyota, 1985 (Box 250)
    - Transportation, 1985-1990 (Box 250)
    - Treasury, 1985-1989; 3 folders (Box 250)
    - Trade Policy, 1987-1989 (Box 250)
    - U of M / MSU Financial Support And Tuition Restraint, 1988 (Box 250)
    - University of Minnesota, 1985-1989 (Box 250)
    - U.S. Constitutional Amendment, 1985 (Box 250)
    - United Way, 1985-1987 (Box 250)
    - Vacations, 1985-1988 (Box 250)
    - Washington Office, 1985-1990 (Box 250)
    - Wayne County, 1987-1989 (Box 250)
    - White Pine Mine, 1985-1987 (Box 250)
    - Whirlpool Site-St., Joseph, 1989 (Box 250)
    - Williams, Soapy, 1985-1988 (Box 250)
    - Women Appointments, 1987 (Box 250)
    - Yes 150 Foundation, 1986 (Box 250)
    - Youth Corps, 1988-1989 (Box 250)
  - Lansing residence events file
    - March 9, 1983-December 20, 1983 (Box 250)
    - January 18, 1984-June 9, 1985 (Box 251)
    - June 16, 1985-September 14, 1988 (Box 252)
    - September 15, 1988-December 20, 1990 (Box 253)
  - Governor's Briefing Notebooks, etc
    - Fiscal year, 1991 (Box 254)
    - Budget overview, 1990 (Box 254)
    - School health education, 1986 (Box 254)
    - Fiscal year appropriation bills, 1990 (Box 254)
    - State of the State Drafts, 1990 (Box 254)
  - Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1982-1990
    - Accomplishments, Annual Reports, 1984-1989 (Box 255)
    - Build Michigan Program (Box 255)
    - Bush, George (Box 255)
    - Clinton, William (Box 255)
    - Correspondence, Incoming, 1989-1990 (Box 255)
    - Education
      - Proposals A and B, 1989 (Box 255)
      - Proposal A, Media (Box 255)
      - Proposal A, Opposition (Box 255)
      - Proposal A, Support (Box 255)
      - Proposal A, Tracking Reports (Box 255)
    - Gast, Harry (Box 255)
    - Gray, William H., III (Box 255)
    - Golf (Box 255)
    - Iacocca, Lee A (Box 255)
    - Insurance Premium Tax (Box 255)
    - Liquor, Sale of (Box 255)
    - Medical Malpractice Report (Box 255)
    - Memoranda, Incoming, 1990 (Box 255)
    - Press Releases, 1990 (Box 255)
    - Reports, Incoming, 1990 (Box 255)
    - Scheduling, Visits, 1986-1990 (Box 255)
    - Signature Requests (Box 255)
    - Speeches
      - 1982-1985 (Box 255)
      - 1986 (Box 255)
      - 1987 (Box 255)
      - 1990 (Box 255)
      - Undated (Box 255)
    - Visual Materials (Box 255)
- Political and Campaign Files
  The Political and Campaign Files series consists largely of polling survey and campaign materials from Blanchard's gubernatorial campaigns in 1982, 1986 and 1990. There are also files relating to Blanchard's work as chairman of the 1988 Democratic Convention Platform Committee.
  - Polling data
    - 1982 Gubernatorial election, 1981-1982
      (polls conducted by Massoglia and Associates)
      - Statewide issues survey, July 1981; 2 volumes
        - Statewide issues survey, July 1981 (Volume 1)
        - Statewide issues survey, July 1981 (Volume 2)
          (continued)
      - 18th Congressional District issues survey, July 1981; 2 volumes
        - 18th Congressional District issues survey, July 1981 (Volume 3)
        - 18th Congressional District issues survey, July 1981 (Volume 4)
      - Primary voters sample, January 1982 (Volume 5)
      - Issues survey, April 1982 (Volume 6)
      - Primary tracking poll, June 1982 (Volume 7)
      - General survey, June 1982 (Volume 8)
      - Tracking survey, July 1982 (Volume 9)
    - 1982 tracking surveys, 1982
      (conducted by Nordhaus Research, Inc.)
      - July-August 1982, 6 volumes (Box 257)
      - September-October 1982, 6 volumes (Box 258)
      - October 1982, 3 volumes (Box 259)
    - Post election surveys
      (conducted by Nordhaus Research)
      - January 1983 (Box 259)
      - May 1983 (Box 259)
      - August 1983, 5 volumes (Box 260)
    - 1986 gubernatorial election, 1984-1986
      - Michigan Political (Survey of issues), August 1984; 3 volumes (Box 261)
        (conducted by Frank N. Magid Associates)
      - Michigan Political (Survey of issues), December 1984 (Box 261)
      - Michigan statewide issues, September 1984; 1 volume, 1 folder (Box 261)
        (prepared for Hameroff-Milenthal by Market Opinion Research)
      - Michigan Political (Survey of issues) III, March 1985 (Box 261)
      - Michigan Survey, November 1985 (Box 262)
      - Michigan Survey, February 1986 (Box 262)
      - Analysis of Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #1 (January 1986), March 10, 1986 (Box 262)
      - Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #2, June 10, 1986; 2 volumes (Box 262)
      - Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #3, July 19, 1986 (Box 262)
      - Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #4, August 23, 1986 (Box 262)
        (includes script used with interviewees)
      - Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #5, September 20, 1986 (Box 263)
      - Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #6, October 24, 1986 (Box 263)
      - Political Opinions, Attitudes, and Behavior in Michigan (Frank N. Magid Associates), January 1985; May 1985; 2 volumes (Box 263)
      - Re Michigan Poll #1, January 1986 (Box 263)
      - Analysis of Michigan Governor's Race, June 1986 (Box 263)
      - Preliminary summary of post-election poll results, December 1986 (Box 263)
      - Polling miscellaneous, 1984-1986; 4 folders (Box 263)
      - Volunteer poll #1, August 5, 1986 (Box 311)
      - Volunteer poll #2, September 12, 1986 (Box 311)
      - Volunteer poll #3, September 25, 1986 (Box 311)
      - Volunteer poll #4, October 3, 1986 (Box 311)
      - Volunteer poll #7, October 27, 1986 (Box 312)
      - Volunteer poll #8, November 3, 1986 (Box 312)
      - 1982-1984 Vote Return Profiles for Every Minor Civil Division (MCD) in Michigan, prepared for Michigan Democratic Party by Market Resource, July 15, 1986, 1982-1986 (Box 312)
      - Vote Return Profiles Rank Order Listings of Selected Targeting Statistics, prepared for Michigan Democratic Party by Market Resource, July 22, 1986 (Box 312)
      - Vote Return Profiles Selected Targeting Statistics for Every Minor Civil Division (MCD) in Michigan, prepared for Michigan Democratic Party by Market Resource, July 22, 1986 (Box 312)
      - Precinct Level Vote Return Profiles Rank Order Listings for Selected Targeting Statistics, prepared for Campaign 1986 by Market Resource, August 4, 1986 (Box 312)
    - Post-election
      - December 18, 1986 (Box 313)
      - "Michigan 'Economic' Poll--December 1986", January 12, 1987 (Box 313)
      - "Michigan Post-election 'Political' Poll--December, 1986", January 12, 1987 (Box 313)
      - October 22, 1987, 3 volumes (Box 313)
      - Analysis of Results of 1987 Michigan Poll, November 1987 (Box 313)
      - Michigan Statewide, May 1987 (Box 313)
      - Michigan Statewide, February 1988 (Box 313)
      - Michigan Statewide, August 1988 (Box 313)
      - Poll script, 1987 (Box 313)
    - 1990 gubernatorial election, 1989-1990
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #1 (Harrison & Goldberg), December 24, 1988, 1988-1990; 4 volumes (Box 314)
      - Analysis of Poll #1, January 1989 (Box 314)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #2 (Harrison & Goldberg), January 2-4, 1990, 2 volumes (Box 314)
      - Analysis of Poll #2, January 15, 1990 (Box 314)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #3 (Harrison & Goldberg), March 23-April 2, 1990, 5 volumes (Box 315)
      - Analysis of Poll #3, April 1990 (Box 315)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #4 (Harrison & Goldberg), June 20-22, 1990, 2 volumes (Box 315)
      - Analysis of Poll #4, June 1990 (Box 316)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #5 (Harrison & Goldberg), July 25-27, 1990 (Box 316)
      - Analysis of Poll #5, July 1990 (Box 316)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #6 (Harrison & Goldberg), August 13-16, 1990, 2 volumes (Box 316)
      - Analysis of Poll #6, August 1990 (Box 316)
      - Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #6 (tabulation), 1990 (Box 316)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #7 (Harrison & Goldberg), September 17-20, 1990 (Box 316)
      - Analysis of Poll #7, September 25, 1990 (Box 316)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #8 (Harrison & Goldberg), October 3-7, 1990 (Box 316)
      - Analysis of Poll #8, October 15, 1990 (Box 316)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #9 (Harrison & Goldberg), October 9-10, 1990 (Box 316)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #10 (Harrison & Goldberg), October 15-17, 1990 (Box 317)
      - Analysis of Poll #10, October 22, 1990 (Box 317)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #11 (Harrison & Goldberg), October 23-24, 1990 (Box 317)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #12 (Harrison & Goldberg), October 26-28, 1990 (Box 317)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #13 (Harrison & Goldberg), October 30-31, 1990 (Box 317)
      - 1990 Michigan Gubernatorial Poll #14 (Harrison & Goldberg), November 1-2, 1990, 2 volumes (Box 317)
      - Polling miscellaneous (Box 317)
      - 1990 gubernatorial volunteer poll, September-October 1990, 6 volumes (Box 264)
      - Michigan Tax Issues Study Presentation Material prepared for Promote Michigan Education Committee, August 1989 (Box 335)
      - Michigan Issues Monitor Survey, September 1989; 1 folder, 1 volume (Box 335)
        (conducted by Market Strategies)
      - Michigan Education Ballot Question Poll #1, October 1989; 1 folder, 1 volume (Box 335)
        (conducted by Harrison & Goldberg)
      - Michigan Democratic Party Poll #10, May 28-30, 1990; 1 volume (Box 335)
      - National Message/Theme Poll, December 26, 1989 (Box 335)
      - Michigan's Democratic Statewide Coordinated Campaign, 1990 (Box 335)
      - Michigan Statewide, Michigan House Democrats, February 1990 (Box 335)
        (The Analysis Group, Inc.)
  - Campaign files
    - Gubernatorial campaign, 1982
      - "A thinking paper on human services in Michigan" (Box 265)
      - Background papers: Public Issues in Michigan (Box 265)
      - Miscellaneous campaign issues (Box 265)
      - Campaign materials (flyers, newsletters) (Box 265)
      - Miscellaneous transition files (include personnel information (Box 265)
      - Economic Revitalization Plan (and campaign materials), 1982 (Box 265)
      - Report of Pre-election Task Force Gubernatorial Transition, 1982 (Box 265)
      - Topical and issues files (Box 318)
      - Topical and issues files (Box 319)
    - Gubernatorial campaign, 1986
      - Issues, strategy, briefing materials (Box 266)
      - Candidate questionnaires (Box 266)
      - Lisa Grayson (Campaign Press Secretary) files (Box 320)
      - Lisa Grayson (Campaign Press Secretary) files (Box 321)
      - Lisa Grayson (Campaign Press Secretary) files (Box 322)
      - Gary Bachula (Campaign Manager) files (Box 323)
      - Gary Bachula (Campaign Manager) files (Box 324)
      - Gary Bachula (Campaign Manager) files (Box 325)
      - Nancy Schertzing (Office Manager) files (Box 326)
    - Gubernatorial campaign, 1990
      - Charles Kolbe files
        (research on John Engler)
        - Charles Kolbe files (Box 327)
        - Charles Kolbe files (Box 328)
      - Research files: Engler and the Issues, 2 volumes (Box 329)
      - Research files: John Engler, 2 volumes (Box 329)
      - Gary Bachula (Campaign Manager) files (Box 330)
      - Unprocessed/unlisted (Box 267)
      - Unprocessed/unlisted (Box 268)
  - Other political activities
    - Midwestern Governors Association (Box 269)
    - National Governors Association (Box 269)
    - Democratic Governors Association (Box 269)
    - Democratic Business Council (Box 269)
    - Democratic Defection Revisited (analysis), April 1, 1987 (Box 269)
    - Presidential campaign, 1988 (Box 269)
    - Democratic Nation Convention Platform Committee, 1988
      (JJB was chair)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 269)
      - Statements and proposed platform recommendations (Box 331)
      - Statements and proposed platform recommendations (Box 332)
      - Official Transcript 1988 Platform Hearing, May 10, 1988, 1 volume (Box 333)
      - The Republican Record, George Bush, 1967-1988 (Box 333)
      - Miscellaneous Policy Papers (Box 333)
      - Memoranda; correspondence; general information; etc. (Box 333)
      - Clippings (Box 333)
  - Fund-raising and miscellaneous
    - Fund-raising events (various gubernatorial campaigns) (Box 334)
      (sampled)
    - Officeholder Expense Fund (summary reports) (Box 334)
    - Blanchard Foundation (Box 334)
    - Christmas cards (Box 334)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 334)
- Governor/Political, 1960s-1990s
  (The Governor/Political series contains files from the governor's residence accessioned in 2002-2005 and contain staff memoranda, polling material, some publications, and miscellaneous materials, among others)
  - Memoranda from staff, 1985-1987 (Box 336)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed (Box 336)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964-1990s (Box 337)
    (unprocessed; include campaign memorabilia)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 270)
  - Telephone call logs (Box 270)
  - Budget and financial miscellaneous (Box 271)
  - Clippings regarding state political figures and JJB, 1980s; 3 volumes (Box 271)
  - Staff (and others) memoranda, 1987-1989; 14 folders (Box 271)
  - General polling material (Box 272)
  - Memoranda/subject files (Box 272)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed (Box 272)
  - Publications (Box 273)
  - Publications (Box 274)
  - Inauguration files (Box 274)
  - Appointments to state boards and commissions (Box 275)
  - Appointments to state boards and commissions (Box 276)
- Post-gubernatorial career 1990s-2000s, 1992
  The series is made up of files from Blanchard's post-gubernatorial career, including his time as ambassador to Canada.
  - Bill Clinton campaign, 1992 (Box 277)
  - Schedules, 1991-1992 (Box 278)
  - Private law practice (Box 279)
  - Organizational interests (Box 279)
  - Center for the Great Lakes (Box 279)
  - Next Century Michigan (Box 279)
  - Anti-voucher campaign (Box 279)
  - Letter to President Clinton outlining his thoughts on the 1996 campaign, 1996 (Box 279)
  - Ambassador to Canada (Box 280)
  - Ambassador to Canada (Box 281)
  - Ambassador to Canada (Box 338)
  - Ambassador to Canada (Box 339)
  - Ambassador to Canada (Box 282)
  - Senatorial candidacy evaluation, 2000 (Box 282)
  - Senatorial candidacy evaluation, 2000 (Box 283)
  - Gubernatorial campaign, 2002
    - Press releases (Box 284)
    - Topical files (Chris Trebilcock; policy and field coordinator; Greg Morris) (Box 284)
    - Notebooks of clippings (issues and candidates) (Box 285)
    - Notebooks of clippings (issues and candidates) (Box 286)
    - Topical files (Box 287)
- Visual Materials
  The series, 1982-2002, contains videotapes and photographs of Blanchard's gubernatorial campaign, his years as governor, and his post-gubernatorial activities.
  - Videotapes
    - Blanchard for Governor television spots, 1982 (Box 288)
    - Blanchard for Governor television spots, 1982 (Box 289)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 290)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 291)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 292)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 293)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 294)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 295)
    - Gubernatorial speeches, appearances, and related (Box 296)
    - Gubernatorial campaign, 1990 (Box 297)
    - Gubernatorial campaign, 1990 (Box 298)
    - Gubernatorial campaign, 1990 (Box 299)
    - Post-gubernatorial activities (include period as ambassador to Canada) (Box 300)
    - Post-gubernatorial activities (include period as ambassador to Canada) (Box 301)
    - Gubernatorial primary campaign, 2002 (Box 302)
    - Gubernatorial primary campaign, 2002 (Box 303)
    - Gubernatorial primary campaign, 2002 (Box 304)
    - Gubernatorial primary campaign, 2002 (Box 305)
    - Gubernatorial primary campaign, 2002 (Box 306)
    - Campaign, 1990s; 2002 (Box 340)
  - Photographs
    - Gubernatorial and post-gubernatorial photographs and albums (Box 307)
    - Gubernatorial and post-gubernatorial photographs and albums (Box 308)